Anmol Jain

Email: anmoljain1201@gmail.com Website: https://anmoljain.vercel.app/ Mobile: +91-6397275143

Github: JainAnmol744 LinkedIn: Anmol Jain

Summary

I am graduating from an IT Engineering program and am looking for a role where I can grow and use my skills. I am a Full-Stack Developer with 1+ year of experience in Full-Stack development. I have the Ability to adapt to change with ease. I am excited to learn innovative technologies and contribute to the success of the company.

EDUCATION

Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University

Kanpur, India

Bachelor of Technology - Information Technology

August 2019 - May 2023

SKILLS SUMMARY

C++, OOPs, Data Structure and Algorithm, SQL • Languages:

• Web Development: React, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Redux, NodeJS, Express

• Tools/Platforms: VS Code, GIT, Github, Atom, Linux, Web, Windows, Postman, Bitbucket

• Soft Skills: Leadership, Event Management, Writing, Problem Solving, Time Management

Experience

EMSEC Pvt. Ltd. Remote

Software Developer (Internship)

March 2023 - Present

- Built a backend API using Express to provide seamless communication between the front-end and the database.
- Developed and deployed several web applications using popular JS frameworks like React JS.
- Created reusable components using React JS to improve development efficiency and maintainability.
- Build the UI using reusable component and implement APIs using Axios.
- Utilized Git for version control to manage changes and collaborate effectively with team members.

Zust Web OPC Pvt. Ltd.

Remote

Frontend Developer (Internship)

May 2022 - July 2022

- o Developing new responsive web applications and maintaining existing web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.js.
- Working with the design team to ensure that the user interface is aesthetically pleasing.
- From using APIs to integration of different services into the website, to creating dynamic user interfaces with JavaScript, I was able to learn a wide range of skills.
- Proficiency working on RESTFUL APIs.
- Collaborating with other engineers to ensure the application meets all user requirements.
- Proficiency working on State management library Redux.

Projects

• Mail-Karo: DEMO

- User Authentication: Users will be able to create accounts and log in to access the chatbox. This will ensure that messages are secure and only visible to authorized users.
- o Inbox and Message Threads: Users will have an inbox where they can see a list of their ongoing conversations. Clicking on a conversation will open the message thread, displaying the messages exchanged between the users.
- o Composing and Sending Messages: Users will be able to compose messages, add recipients, and send them. The chatbox should support both plain text and rich text formatting options (such as bold, italics, bullet points, etc.) to enhance the message content.
- Implemented GET/POST/PUT requests to firebase in order to retrieve user-specific information for each user
- o Frontend used HTML, CSS, Javascript, React, Redux and Bootstrap

• Netflix-clone: DEMO

- Users would be able to browse a library of movies and TV shows, filtered by categories such as trending, popular, and
- The application would include a video player for users to watch movies and TV shows on the platform.
- Users would be able to create and manage their watchlists, save their favorite shows and movies.
- The application would be optimized for different screen sizes and devices to ensure a seamless user experience on desktop and mobile devices.

CERTIFICATION

Cisco Educational Academy on JavaScript Essentials, July 2022:

- Understands the fundamentals of JavaScript and the way they are used in web development.
- Learned the essential concepts of programming, including variables, data structures, algorithms, control flow, functions, and exceptions.

Volunteer Experience

- o Event Co-ordinator of Annual Sports Fest of College (AAVEG) Kanpur, India.
- Volunteered for institute parades and social service campaigns.
- Led the group of students responsible for working on different. verticals of the group like management, technical, editorial.